June, 1950,
the Korean war broke out on full scale.
On June 27th, the U.S. 7th fleet
sailed into the Taiwanese ports
of keelung and kaohsiung,
where they carried out
reconnoiter and patrol operations,
as well as military exercise.
On September 15th,
the x corps of the U.S.
army landed in inchon,
where they marched north
joined by the "UN. Forces".
Thousands of aircrafts of
the U.S. far east airforce
entered Chinese territorial space,
warfare spreading to the yalu river.
China's territorial sovereignty
and national security
were under severe threat.
In response to the
provocative action on the invaders' part,
as requested by the dprk,
the Chinese government,
after deliberate consideration,
decided to send troops to North Korea.
On October 25th,
the pva engaged the enemy
for the first time since
they entered North Korea,
starting the quest to
aid Korean allies against the Americans.
Back in the day the prc had just founded.
The industrial system was incomplete,
the air force was insubstantial
and ammunition was in extreme shortage.
The fight was a demonstration
for consolidating the new regime
as well as establishing
China's image on the international stage.
The stake was extremely high.
By 1953,
after two periods of arduous warfare,
the pva managed to shift
from defensive to offensive,
mid-July,
the pva launched the third-stage action
of summer counterstrike,
centered around the battle of kumsong
this will be the final combat.
Winning this battle
would make us the ultimate Victor
in the war against the
American invasion of North Korea.
A division code-named yanshan unit
was ordered to reinforce the frontline
by covering the main force
at right flank in the general offensive.
Should they fail to reach the
assigned location by 06:00 in the morning,
the entire corps would have to
dive into a pack of wolves
like a hawk with broken wings,
getting themselves in grave peril.
The situation couldn't be more dire.
And that was when the
rapids of kumgang river
stood ruthlessly
in their way.
Sir,
do you hear that?
Canons are being fired in kumgsong, listen.
Xiao hu,
you think you've grown smarter now?
How could you possibly know
from tens of kilometers away?
It's just thunder.
No way!
The fight must have started.
What took the engineer battalion so long
to fix that bridge anyway?
Don't they know
tens of thousands of men are waiting?
Shut up!
Keep your ass on the ground.
Attention, everyone!
All units keep close!
Stick to the route, on the double!
No man falls behind!
Move!
Come on! Catch up!
- All of you, chop-chop!
- 3rd squad, follow me!
At that time,
I had just joined the army.
They all called me xiao hu.
American planes
flew over us every single day.
I wished we had some planes to protect us.
But we only had a few
and they were all at the front.
There's nothing we could do.
Our squad leader
was obsessed with the idea
of getting into action
and winning a medal.
He told me that,
only by winning the final combat
could we go home
and live a peaceful life.
Cross the river in turn!
But fast!
The whole division have to
cross the kumgang in an hour!
Cross the river in turn!
On the double!
Division.
Advance force of yanshan unit
had made contact with engineer company.
All troops follow in turn.
Request instruction whether
to cross the river immediately!
Advance company,
cross the river as planned.
All units of 301 regiment,
cross the river in turn.
302 and 303 regiments,
follow up and take cover.
Do not expose tracks of the main force.
Await further instruction.
All operations shall be
carried out at night if necessary.
Yes, copy that.
At the time,
there's only one way
to the kumsong front,
a tactical military bridge.
Every single one of us
wanted to engage the
enemy across the river.
However,
that deep impetuous river
stopped us.
I see.
You didn't even get us one single shell.
The bridge is about to be rejoined
and the main force should be
on the other side now.
Not yet.
Advance force of yanshan unit has
made contact with engineer company,
just arriving at the shoal.
A recon plane just dropped by,
that could mean the harbingers
Are coming, then we are done.
If only you had brought in some extra ammo
we could've shot
those flies Down,
and they'll be the ones going blind.
Then we'll dominate the night time.
That won't happen even with extra ammo.
The recon planes are too damn fast.
And we're not using
slingshots here, either.
Get cocky all they want,
but I can take them all out if
they would just dive a little lower.
We can't get the shells over here.
There's nothing the lieutenant can do.
Our company
already donated two guns to the other guys.
Another three are being mended.
That leaves us with just two.
We can't possibly give any more.
Then fire them together.
Lieutenant's order.
No firing them together.
Two guns.
Number one and number two,
the latter being a concealed emplacement.
Can't risk exposing it
unless it's absolutely necessary.
That's the plan.
Concealed emplacement.
You'll be in charge of that.
And I got number one.
Also,
from now on,
I call the shots here.
Sergeant guan,
lieutenant's orders.
Sure.
I'm thinking,
maybe I should take the one in front
and you go to the concealed emplacement.
Second lieutenant zhang,
everyone, hurry up.
The bridge is about to be rejoined.
Hurry!
Say...
Follow up!
Take cover!
The harbingers! Get down.
Regiment, regiment,
this is the 8th company.
Regiment, this is the 8th company.
Do you copy?
Did you get through to the regiment?
I'm on it.
What about the engineer company?
I'm trying.
This is the 8th company.
Engineer company,
regiment, do you copy?
The bridge is gone.
It's a recon plane, take cover!
Take cover.
Engineer company. Hurry. Fix the bridge.
Five degrees to the right.
- Got him.
- It's the aa guns.
- Fantastic.
- It's our aa guns.
Regiment.
Regiment, this is the 8th company.
Sir, regiment is on.
Hello.
What? It's damaged?
How bad is it?
Four meters?
Hello?
Lao gao.
How bad is the damage?
Can our company cross first?
You know what?
Xiao hu and I will go first.
Find a way around.
Are you saying that you're smarter than me?
You think the bridge's gonna fix it itself?
That somehow it requires no time?
Just wait.
Take cover.
When are we going to cross
the river now that the bridge is gone?
That's right.
And we've been waiting for so long.
Qiao,
if you're still alive,
we'd be going to kumsong together.
Now,
I'll take you there.
Rest assured.
When we get to kumsong,
I'll win one of them medals for you boys.
Sir,
have some water.
Fuck off.
You keep staring at that photo.
Regiment.
Hello.
Too much inference.
That's the new operator girl regiment sent,
I heard she's from sichuan, too.
You guys must have a special bond.
She doesn't even know my name.
What special bond?
But I do know that
she's from wusheng county, nanchong.
A place called yankou.
We just never talked.
Special bond my ass.
Sir, examination complete.
We can cross whenever we're ready.
Inform division,
bridge is now fixed.
Preparing to cross.
Yes, sir.
- Off the bridge.
- Now.
Clean up the bridge.
Yes, sir.
Rejoining complete.
We can cross in ten minutes.
Yes, sir.
Hurry!
Assemble!
Quick! 2nd unit assemble!
We need more hands here.
Get the pile driver moving.
Sir.
Word of command!
Kumgang river!
- After we crossed...
- Lieutenant gao,
lieutenant gao,
the colonel asked me
to tell you this in person
for it's too complicated
to explain over radio.
Have some water first.
Colonel's order.
To make sure we arrive
at kumsong tomorrow at 0600 hours,
our troops must cross the river
before 0500 tomorrow morning.
Understood.
And there's been
a change of plan for your company.
You'll be the last to cross
and under the engineer company's command.
They'll tell you what to do and when.
But, how does it work exactly?
Once they run into any trouble
you guys are up.
Fix the bridge.
Lao gao.
Fix the bridge?
I see.
Consider it done.
- Xin qin.
- Yes, sir.
Tell the engineer company
to keep us posted on the
fixing progress every 30 minutes.
Yes, sir.
- First squad.
- Present.
- Second squad.
Lao gao.
Pack up your gears,
get ready for fixing the bridge.
Yes, sir.
Lao gao, why us again?
It was us the last time,
and this time, too.
Surely we're not doing this every time?
We're here to fight,
not fixing Bridges.
You don't think that's part of the job?
How are we gonna fight
when the bridge's broken?
Are you out of your mind?
You promised me
that I'll win a medal for the boys.
Everyone wants a medal.
I know exactly what you think.
It won't stop you from winning anything.
Talk with your tongue
straightened out, would you?
Excuse me?
I'm just saying.
Every time you get mad
you start speaking in jiangxi dialect.
Like anyone understands that gibberish.
I didn't make out a word you said.
Your words don't make any sense to me too.
See, now you're not making any sense again.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Do you understand me?
I'm not thirsty.
Are you fucking kidding me?
The recon plane is back.
Take cover, take cover.
2nd and 3rd company cross in ten minutes.
Get moving!
Recon plane!
All units, take cover immediately!
Engineer company, get ready to take fire!
Rear units fall back!
Advance units speed up the crossing!
Damn howitzer!
Everyone, fan out and take cover!
Howitzer!
- Fan out!
- Take cover!
Take cover!
Howitzer!
Medic!
Everyone down!
It's not over yet.
- Get down.
- Yes, sir.
Check casualties.
This is the 8th company.
Engineer company, do you copy?
- Did you get through to engineer company?
- Not yet.
There goes the bridge again.
Sir, signal's completely gone now.
We have to go to the engineer company.
We'll keep you guys posted.
Good.
- Be safe out there.
- Yes, sir.
- Lao lu.
- Sir.
Bring two men with them.
Yes, sir.
- You two, follow me.
- Sir,
we need to find another high ground
to set the radio.
The signal's less likely
to be scrambled up above.
We can send back intel
about the shoal from there.
- Got it.
- Move.
- Stay safe.
- Yes, sir.
- Liu hao.
- Sir.
Do you understand what xin oin said?
Go higher and find signal.
Yes, sir.
- I need two operators.
- Sir.
Third squad, follow me.
Yes, sir.
Take your torches.
- Keep an eye on the harbingers.
- What's this for?
You talk too much.
You'll be on high ground.
Send signals in time.
Yes, sir.
Comrades.
This bridge
is our lifeline.
Let's show the Americans
that this bridge
could not be destroyed by them.
All other Bridges have been ruined.
This wooden bridge is our last hope.
Come on!
Move the ammo forward, quick.
Clock is ticking, follow me.
You boys, come with me.
Now, move the ammo forward
and put them together.
Lao San, you contact regiment,
I'll try and reach lieutenant gao.
Yes, sir.
Now,
take your men to the hilltop.
Roger. Let's go.
Go.
- Heizi, erhu, - sir.
Disperse and go in.
Stand watch for the other side.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
Go.
Third squad. Get the timber to the bridge.
Hilltop, is the transfer in position?
Affirmative.
What's the situation at the shoal?
Haven't received any reports from there.
Something's wrong.
"Something's wrong."
"Roger that."
Take position.
- Gunner one in position.
- Gunner three in position.
- Gunner two in position.
- Gunner four in position.
Comrade, who's your commander?
The second lieutenant.
Come on.
Sir.
What's this? State your department.
We are signalers from the 8th company.
What's the situation on the bridge now?
Estimated time of recovery, 0300 hours.
We couldn't get any signal
so they sent me here.
You can set up your
station behind that tank.
Yes, sir.
Go now,
it's safer there.
Hurry.
It's been hit.
Bravo.
What are you doing?
Stay low.
Don't give away our location.
Engineer company!
Hurry.
Fix the bridge.
Hurry. Hurry up.
Hilltop, pass the intel on to division.
Sir.
Sir, communication from the shoal.
Visible breach of seven
meters on the bridge.
Breach of seven meters.
Estimated time of recovery, 0300 hours.
Under attack by enemy jets now.
Hilltop copy.
Reporting to division now.
Regiment.
Visible breach of seven
meters on the bridge.
Sir, is this our katyushu?
Shut up.
So much ammo.
Shoal, this is division.
Enemy artillery destroyed by katyusha.
Fix the bridge asap.
Xin qin.
Sir.
Latest update.
Fixing almost done.
- Report to division immediately.
- Yes, sir.
- Tell all units to get ready.
- You come with me.
- Yes, sir.
Stay safe.
Zhang fei.
Hurry, clean up the road!
Clear out a passage
for the troops crossing!
This is gao fulai, get me liu hao.
Lieutenant gao is on the line.
The company will
cross the bridge in ten minutes.
You boys on the 3rd squad has one job only.
Watch out for enemy jets.
Do you copy?
Copy.
Hilltop, hilltop.
Hilltop copy.
The company can
cross the bridge in ten minutes.
I repeat,
the company can
cross the bridge in ten minutes.
Hilltop copy.
Reporting to division now.
Regiment, this is hilltop.
The company can
cross the bridge in ten minutes.
I repeat, the company can
Clock is ticking.
Clean up the bridge.
The company can
cross the bridge in ten minutes.
Hurry.
Division assemble,
bridge rejoined in five minutes.
Companies get on the bridge,
cross according to plan.
2nd company,
3rd battalion, 1st regiment, after me.
Hurry, catch up.
3rd company, after me.
Hurry.
Other units follow up.
On the double, come on.
Hurry.
Three meters between each row.
Maintain formation.
Don't squeeze, cross in turn.
Get me shoal.
Shoal, come in, do you copy?
Shoal copy.
Kill the lights,
incoming enemy jets, get through asap.
Kill the lights, get through asap.
Comrade xin oin, I...
See you at the front.
Comrade liu hao.
Torch.
Clock is ticking, hurry up.
Sir, main force is crossing.
How many rounds do we have left?
Forty-one.
Five tracers.
Let's show him
we're here.
Gunners take position.
Kill the lights, get through asap.
Watch you feet.
As a matter of fact,
we had been keeping a close eye
on our boys on the other side.
But that's the thing about battlefields.
You don't always know
who they are
or their names.
You just know they're on your side.
And that they got us through the bridge.
Chances are,
you may never see each other again.
Sir.
It's like suicide.
No one knew
what really happened there.
But in a sense we did know.
What else could it be
but sacrifice?
I'm going over there to help.
- Sir.
- You two guard here well.
They are fighting on the other side.
All units that
aren't on the bridge, take cover now.
Do not expose yourselves.
Rear units stop crossing.
Advance units speed up the crossing.
Lao gao.
No man falls behind, catch up.
Let me cross and help them.
What will you do?
You can't even help yourself.
Watch out! Bombs in the water.
- Engineer company.
- Yes, sir.
Hurry, go help.
Yes, sir.
Go help.
Lao gao.
Hang on there.
Medic.
Comrade operator. Hang in there.
I need a stretcher.
Someone fix the bridge.
Recon planes.
More hands here. Push the tank down.
Block the breach.
Lao gao.
Leave me.
Go fix the bridge.
Keep pushing.
Good swimmers of the 7th company.
Sir.
Everyone.
Shoulder arms.
We're crossing the river first.
- Yes, sir.
There's undercurrent four meters under.
Swimming across is not an option.
The attack begins at six or does it not?
You want to be
held responsible for delaying it?
Yes.
I'm responsible for whatever goes on here.
And I'm going to join them now.
The only way to the other side
is through that bridge.
The harbinger is here.
Fan out and take cover.
Take cover now.
Take cover now!
Get down.
You can't stop me.
You just can't.
Old Smith: You know,
lots of people are
terrified to take a flight.
There are fears in their mind,
just like what I feel now.
But can you imagine,
once,
I was a us. Air force pilot.
The first angel sounded his trumpet,
and there came hail
and fire mixed with blood,
and it was hurled down upon the earth.
A third of the earth was burned up.
And... hmm...
A third of the trees were burned up.
And all the green grass was burned up.
The second angel sounded his trumpet,
and something like a huge mountain,
all ablaze, was thrown into the sea...
Warthog,
that is some poetry.
But please confirm
the b26s have hit the target first.
This is no poetry but
the book of resolution, sweetheart.
And yeah, this is the view I see.
It's called the book
of revelations, cowboy.
Whatever, it is what I see.
This is mole,
the bz6s were accurate
and the target has been hit.
The delayed-action bombs are in position.
Copy, cowboys.
Now please proceed damage assessment.
Alright.
Lower altitude.
Initiating damage assessment.
Old Smith: The sky belonged to us.
Their weapons were a joke.
I heard the Chinese use two sticks to eat.
They don't even know
how to build a bicycle.
But it was the oddest thing
that bridge just...
Just keep getting fixed.
And my mission seemed to never end.
See you in never.
Sir.
Why won't they just blow up?
Atc! Atc! We are under attack.
Warthog, warthog, what's your status?
There's an aa gun one hundred
and fifty yards west to the target.
Can you return fire?
Negative. No ammo. Damn it!
Fucking chinks!
No chute.
The kid is dead.
Do you hear me?
The kid is kia.
Hey hill, I heard from
my pal in the army that
they lost forty thousand men last month?
We are lucky up here you know?
Right? Right, hill?
Hey hill, listen,
I heard my cousin in the Navy said
that they've got this
big fat negotiation coming up,
and this war is gonna be over soon.
You know what I mean, right?
Just cut the crap.
What do you want?
Come on.
What are we doing here?
We should just drop the bomb and go home.
You know what I mean?
I don't wanna die here.
You know? Just tell me how many
flaks have they got down there, ok?
I mean... you saw them
clearly last time, right?
- Right?
- Shut up.
The major battleground
is right there, in front of us.
Without the bridge,
it's their hell.
With it standing,
it's ours.
What the...
Is that the bridge?
Didn't you just bomb
this bridge 3 hours ago?
Jesus.
That bridge could
take our sappers three days easy.
I've had enough.
Why can't we blow this bridge up?
You know what?
They just won't die.
You need fire to burn them out.
Atc, this is warthog!
Target bridge Alpha 4006 is resumed.
Calling for m155 attack!
Repeat, calling for m155 attack!
The recon plane is coming.
Take cover, now.
Felhunter, this is Smith.
Target bridge Alpha 4006, coords
golf 5-3-0-8, target confirmed.
Fire support, m155 loading.
No.3 barrel loaded. Contact fuze.
Loaded. Fire!
Ejection.
Take cover. Howitzer.
Regiment, we're taking heavy fire.
Soldiers down, soldiers down.
Do you copy?
That's a miss...
- Maybe you can...
- Listen to me.
Target bridge is missed by fifty yards
to the left. Two hundred yards over.
Reduce the radius. Rapid fire!
Copy.
1 mil to the right, 2 low! Fire!
The third angel sounded his trumpet,
and a great star, blazing like a torch,
Fell from the sky on a third of
the rivers and on the Springs of water...
Good kill!
Target bridge is down!
I repeat, this fucking bridge is down!
Felhunter, copy that.
Atc, we are rtb now.
Eta 10 minutes.
Copy.
Warthog, the track is ready.
And you're clear for landing.
Warthog, out.
Hey hill, Jesus. Where are you going!
Hill, hill, our mission's complete!
Smith, keep your altitude.
I gotta do some personal.
This is my leisure time.
Hill, we gotta go back!
Is that, is that gun shot?
What are you doing?
Hill! Pull up! Pull up!
Come on.
Mother of lord! Hill!
Your blood is spilling all over.
Are you dying? You are dying!
- Atc, atc! Warthog is down,
- shut the fuck up.
- I repeat, warthog is down!
- I'm still here.
Warthog, what's your status?
Please respond.
Warthog, respond immediately.
Coords golf 5-3-0-9,
calling for immediate attack!
I repeat, there's a hidden flak.
There's a hidden flak.
Copy. Coords confirm.
Eta 3 minutes.
Incoming, enemy katyusha.
Break! Break! Break!
Sir.
It's our katyusha.
Shut up.
Hold on.
What's that sound?
Taking heavy!
Taking heavy! This is felhunter...
That's our artillery position!
There's hundreds of troops!
God damn it!
How did they do it? This is unbelievable!
I don't wanna die here.
Let's get the hell outta here, man.
Hill, you took off without permission.
Please return immediately.
Otherwise you will
face prosecution by military court.
Give me that.
Hill Andrew!
Give my god damn plane
back you son of a bitch.
Who do you think
you are, you crazy little shit!
Do you hear me! Rtb immediately...
Division assemble,
bridge'll be rejoined in five minutes.
Companies get on the bridge,
cross according to plan.
2nd company,
3rd battalion, 1st regiment, after me.
Hurry, follow me.
3rd company, after me.
Crossing now.
On the double.
Three meters between
each row, crossing now!
Three meters between each row.
Come on.
There you are.
You wanna fight, yeah?
It's just you and me now.
Twelve o'clock.
You wanna hold this bridge?
You gotta pay for it!
You little bastard!
I'm coming for you!
Nice trap. Well done, buddy.
Delayed-action bombs' been activated.
And the second aa gun is down.
But the bridge will be fixed again.
Bring out the big guys.
That's my cowboy!
Smith is escorting
thunderbird to your position.
Good hunting gentleman.
That's a big guy.
Thunderbird, enemy anti-air
defense has been neutralized.
You're clear for low-altitude attack.
Thunderbird copy.
Lowering altitude to 9,000 feet.
Ready to attack.
Show time.
You are still here.
You are out this time.
Atc, atc.
Warthog has been hit.
I repeat, warthog has been hit.
Hill is kia. Hill is kia.
Roger that.
Smith, raise your altitude,
keep circling the position,
and await further instruction.
Everyone, hurry up.
The bridge is about to be rejoined.
Hurry!
Keep it moving.
Lieutenant yan,
the bridge is pretty much fixed.
Everyone pull out with your tools.
Yes, sir.
Everyone, away from the river, now.
- Yes, sir.
- Move now.
Faster.
2nd platoon, keep moving.
Lao Yang.
Three meters between each unit.
Yes, sir.
Prepare to cross.
Three meters between each unit.
The kumgang bridge was just rejoined.
Inform the division,
we're about to cross now.
Yes, sir.
Assemble.
Stop.
Three meters apart, prepare to cross.
The harbingers are here.
All units, take cover.
Fall back. Take cover.
Now. Take cover.
Hurry.
Take cover.
Stay down.
Engineer company.
Hurry.
Fix the bridge.
Target location.
Three o'clock.
Height 4,200, distance 5,100.
Height 4,200.
Target locked on.
Out of range.
- Target location.
- Adjust.
Nine o'clock.
Height 3,800, distance 4,300.
Target locked on.
Out of range.
Height 2,800, distance 11,000.
- Target locked on.
- Can't hit them out of range.
Target locked on.
Not enough height, I don't have a shot.
Five degrees to the right.
Lao guan, I only got 28 rounds left.
Target locked on.
I only got 28 rounds left.
It's too fast.
I got him.
It's been hit.
Bravo.
- Next target.
- Yes, sir.
Now this one is out of my reach.
I'm not gonna mess around.
Lao guan, we don't have many rounds left.
Load, five degrees to the right.
- Heizi, track it.
- Yes, sir.
Let go.
Loadil
lieutenant guan, it's him...
Who do you listen to, me or him?
You're not the company commander anymore.
There's no hitting that one.
I'm just a private now,
but I'm still your fucking master.
Retract.
The bombers are too high
and the recon planes are too fast.
Five,
ten...
Anymore?
There're some in here.
Eighteen rounds.
That's all we got.
And ten thousand men are supposed to
cross the river before five in the morning.
How many times do you
reckon they'll come back?
That's not your excuse for
using the canon like a sniper rifle.
Zhang fei.
Zhang fei, oh, zhang fei.
Why you're named after a legendary warrior
known to everyone in China.
I had no idea. What were
your parents thinking?
Why did they give you such a name?
Just look at you.
If this is your spot,
don't mention the plane,
you can even hit a fly.
Don't hog the spot if
you're not gonna use it.
Go to the emplacement in the back.
The company commander assigned me here.
And he assigned you that one.
If I were still the company commander...
Get out of my face
and go to the back.
There's a hundred rounds back there,
you should feel lucky.
Don't come over here unless I tell you to.
It's not gonna be exposed during the day.
You were demoted from
company commander to squad leader
because of smoking.
Yet you're still doing it.
Fuck off.
Behold, the man shivers
before the kumgang bridge,
scratching his head
when he can hit no plane.
Oh, the man pees in his pants
before the kumgang river,
what a shame to someone named zhang fei.
Sir.
At ease!
Count off.
1,2, 3,4, 5, 6, 7.
One missing.
What, am I not a person?
Sure you are.
Sir,
we only got 46 rounds left.
Goddamn Lao guan.
Sir.
Keep it moving.
Come on.
Sir, examination complete.
We can cross whenever we're ready.
Inform division, the bridge is fixed.
Prepare for crossing.
Hurry up!
Assemble.
Come on, 2nd platoon assemble.
2nd and 3rd company assemble.
Vacant the bridge,
we're moving the vehicles.
The crane will have to wait.
Something's wrong with the wheels.
They're working on it.
Give us a minute.
Clean up the bridge, now.
Maybe
you should return to your emplacement
and leave things be here.
It's getting dark and we're about to cross.
Return to your emplacement.
We should stick to the plan.
The plan was
you guard that gun back there well.
We only have two.
And it's not like we
can fire them together.
We don't want to show the enemy all we got.
Whether our men can
make it across before five
and get to kumsong by six,
so we'd have a shot
at winning the battle...
Second lieutenant zhang,
it's all up to you now.
What's your problem?
Should we switch
the emplacement to another spot?
This location is compromised.
Nope.
We got pretty good
view and range from here.
The higher the further.
Like peeing into the wind.
Good view could mean danger.
You're already a sitting duck.
Why don't you
give me ten rounds of your shells.
Our of compassion, maybe?
Sure.
Fuck off.
I need more hands.
Get the crane out of here.
One, two, three.
2nd and 3rd company cross in ten minutes.
Speed up the crossing.
On the double.
Three meters between each unit.
Do not squeeze.
Cross in turn.
It's a recon plane.
All units, take cover.
Engineer company, get ready to take fire.
Rear units fall back.
Advance units speed up the crossing.
Engineer company, take cover.
Get down.
Gunners take position.
Load it, two o'clock.
Loaded.
Sir, this is a concealed emplacement.
We can't expose it.
Sergeant told us to conceal it.
For how much longer?
Evacuate now.
Take cover.
Zhang fei.
The main force was hit.
Missed.
They were aiming at the bridge.
Engineer company.
Fix the bridge.
Now.
Someone go down and check the deck.
Put out the fire first.
Fix the deck, now.
Hurry up.
Our men are waiting to cross.
Yes, sir.
This way.
Smart-pants,
where's zhang fei?
He's chilling up there.
Tell him to ask guan
about the tobacco he promised me.
Tobacco?
How's the bridge-fixing going?
When can our boys cross it?
Leave that to us.
You go shoot down one of 'em planes.
C'mon.
How soon can they rejoin the bridge?
Sir,
didn't you say guan and
his squad were exposed?
Why aren't they taking any fire?
Stop talking crazy.
Something's wrong.
Definitely not right.
Roger that.
Take position.
- Gunner one in position.
- Gunner three in position.
- Gunner two in position.
- Number four in position.
Gunner in position.
- Gunner three in position.
- Gunner four in position
number five in position.
Six o'clock.
Twelve o'clock.
Load.
Son of a bitch is coming right at us.
Loaded.
Five degrees to the left.
Sir, we are out of rounds.
Get your guns.
Locking on target.
Sir, I got him.
Saliva, take my place.
Yes, sir.
It's our katyusha.
Katyusha.
Sir.
The 1st squad has all settled down.
We are waiting for you
to Bury sergeant guan.
Sir.
Third squad,
check the Cannon position.
Check the Cannon position,
see if they need any help.
- Move now.
- Yes, sir.
No need.
We don't need any help.
Come down you guys.
The bridge need to be reinforced, get down.
Zhang fei.
I was looking for you.
Lao guan,
he's gone.
You guys buried him?
You're the last ones.
Keep fixing the bridge.
Sir, the bridge will be fixed in ten.
- Inform division.
- Yes, sir.
Watch your steps.
- Nails everywhere.
- Yes, sir.
Don't get your feet pierced.
He's back.
It's him again.
How do you even know?
I just know.
Sir.
This is bad.
The main force is crossing now.
How many rounds do we have left?
Forty-one.
Five tracers.
Let's show him
that we're here.
Gunners.
Take position.
Number four in position.
Number five in position.
Tracers.
Loaded.
Adjust.
Load.
Ammo loaded.
Rear units keep up.
Speed up the crossing.
Light it up.
Light it.
Yes, sir.
Lighted.
- Lighted.
- Take position.
Yes, sir.
Sir.
It's like suicide.
Two o'clock.
Twelve o'clock.
Get down.
Keep at the motherfucker.
Shoot him down.
Load.
Yes, sir.
Don't you run.
Let's finish what we started.
Loaded.
Load.
Yes, sir.
Six o'clock.
Sir,
I got no angle.
Wait till he's at three o'clock.
Yes, sir.
I am coming for you.
Come on.
Rear units take cover.
Advance units speed up the crossing.
Now.
Take cover.
Do not expose.
Careful! Bombs in the water!
Bombs in the water! Be careful.
Hurry. Go help.
Hurry.
The harbingers are here. Take cover.
The harbingers are here.
At the foot of changbanpo.
I came to the rescue of zhao yun
and scared off
cao's army
of a million men
it is I,
zhang fei
courtesy name
yide
I shall go down in history
as one reckless man
Atc. Warthog has been hit.
Hill is kia.
Smith, raise your altitude,
keep circling the position,
and await further instruction.
Guan, we got him.
Old Smith: Till this day.
I still smell the burning air.
Hill was lucky,
he went straight to hell.
But for me,
I'm still living in it.
And there's no home for me to go back to.
The target has been completely destroyed.
Requesting rtb now.
My eyes...
Got burnt bad.
And I could see nothing.
To this day,
I can still remember
the smell of something burning.
All around me people were dying.
However, at that time,
believe it or not,
none of the boys
was afraid.
Back in the day,
we were just a bunch of teenagers.
The only thing on our minds
was crossing that bridge
and fending off
the Americans.
We all knew that
if we won this battle,
we would bring
peace
to our people.
Smith,
there's still sign of activities
on bridge Alpha 4-0-0-6.
The last bombing was just half an hour ago.
It's impossible to fix that bridge.
Impossible is their weapon.
Go for a scout.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Atc, I'm in position.
What the...
There's the bridge.
Atc, requesting for bomber support.
Roger that, support is on the way.
One day,
I ran into this American veteran.
And he still remembers
that bridge made of human flesh.
He said,
I know you folks don't believe in god.
But what you did
was nothing short of a miracle.
It's just humanly impossible.
And somehow
you guys pulled it off.
The army has crossed the bridge.
There is no point in attacking now.
There is nothing we can do to stop them.
Bomber squad is ready to attack.
Smith, keep your altitude.
For a new republic
to earn its place
in the world,
and for our people
to have a better life,
soldiers had fought and died,
and they brought honor to the nation.
As is sung in our national anthem,
with our flesh,
a new great wall was built.
Each and everyone of us
knew clearly then,
the happiness of future generations
depended on us.
And that's what kept us going.